Alberto Soragna



🖺 alberto.soragna@gmail.com 🗼 Hartington Road, London UK 🚺 alsora.github.io





ABOUT ME



I'm a robotics engineer working on mobile robotics and SLAM. I have a deep passion for programming and an industrial expertise with many different languages. I'm an active contributor to many well-known open source projects, such as ROS 2. I enjoy practicing sports and working on CS hobby projects involving machine learning and front-end development.

LANGUAGES



Italian: Mothertongue

告 English: Professional proficiency

Ohinese: Basic spoken

SKILLS



TECH SKILLS

3+ years experience with C++ Libraries: Eigen, OpenCV, ROS 3+ years experience with Python Libraries: Numpy, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow Worked on several projects using Bash, C, Java, JavaScript, Matlab Daily user of Docker, Git, LaTeX

SOFT SKILLS

Fast Learner

I'm always curious and eager to learn new concepts in any subject I encounter. Problem Solver

My objective-driven mindset allows me to quickly find scalable solutions to everyday issues.

Independent

I'm capable of working and of organizing duties with small or no supervision.

Communicator

I have done several publich speeches and created effective presentation slides.

EXPERIENCE



Robot

KUKA

iRobot | Robotics & Vision Engineer

August 2018 - Present Pasadena. CA Design of the software architecture for floorcare consumer mobile robots. C++ implementation of sensor processing and navigation algorithms. Profiling and optimization of pub-sub communication mechanisms.

MusixMatch Data Scientist, Machine Learning & Al

January 2018 - July 2018 Bologna, Italy Implementation and deployment of Machine Learning, statistics and deep neural network techniques for NLP. Creation of NLP pipeline for lyrics processing. Dataset collection and features engineering.

KUKA Robotics | Software Developer

July 2017 - January 2018 ♀ Augsburg, Germany Master Thesis student in the Mobile Robotics Navigation team. Development of algorithms for the exploration of industrial environments, active

Simultaneous Localization And Mapping, map representation.



EDUCATION



September 2015 - January 2018 Rome, Italy Final Grade: 110/110 Summa cum Laude | Dissertation: "Active SLAM using Connectivity Graphs as Prior" Advisor: Prof. Giorgio Grisetti

Study Emphases: Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Mobile Robotics, Neural Networks, Probabilistic Robotics

ALMA MATER STUDIORUM

| BSc. Automation Engineering ♥ Bologna, Italy

September 2012 - June 2015 Final Grade: 109/110 | Dissertation: "Design and Implementation of the Guidance Law for a Quadrotor Aerial Vehicle" Advisor: Prof. Lorenzo Marconi Study Emphases: Automatic Controls, Computer Science, Control System Technologies, Control Theory, Electric Drives, Mathematics

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATES



2017 Sapienza University Excellence Path

2013 AlmaTong Double-Degree Scholarship

PUBLICATIONS



2019 A. Soragna, J. Oxoby, and D. Goel. Ros2 for consumer robotics. ROSCon, 2019.

> A. Soragna, Baldini M., Joho D., Kuemmerle R., and Grisetti G. Active slam using connectivity graphs as priors. IROS, 2019.

2018 A. Soragna, Baldini M., and Kuemmerle R. Optimal graph exploration with active loop closure. European patent, 2018.

> A. Soragna, Baldini M., and Joho D. Online adaptation of a prior topology graph to the observed environment during autonomous exploration. European patent, 2018.